Kalkidan Tesfaye

Contact

• Address:

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

• Phone:

+251 942793296

• Email:

kal05627356@gmail.com

Linked in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kalkidan-tesfaye-4376a51a9/

Languages

- English
- Amharic

Summary of Qualification

My obsession and skill on technologies is proven with the things I have done for the past four years like involving in different innovation club, hackathons, schools and even dedicating my summer breaks to stay at campus and work on software projects.

Education

•	Software engineering at Addis Ababa Science and Technology University (3.04/4 GPA)	2016 - 2021
•	ICT Computer Maintenance and Networking at Akaki Polytechnic.	2019 - 2020
•	Kombolcha preparatory school Scoring (490/700)	2015 - 2016
•	Kombolcha millennium high schoo (4/4)	2014 - 2015

Skill

- Programming: Outstanding skills at Java, JavaScript, PHP, Dart and good understanding of c++ and python.
- · Frameworks:- NodeJs, Laravel, Angular and Flutter
- Tools and Approach:- Project management (trello, agile), version controlling system (GIT), postman, cpanel, graphics design tool (Photoshop and illustrator), command line tool

Experience

Self Employed, online and personal Instructor

2018 - 2010

- Taught programming such as java and dart.
- Taught web design and development in html, css, js and php.
- Taught mobile application development in flutter and firebase
- · Built a website that register students online

Website Developer

AASTU Innovation Center, 2019 - 2020

- Built Food Ordering and Delivery a platform which connects customers and a number of restaurants online.
- Built a platform used to sell used books online.
- innovated ideas and solved problems

Backend Developer

Gebeya Training, 2020

- Worked as backend engineer with 5 members of a team to build CV compiler software.
- Practiced agile development methodologies and worked with current ci/cd tools and git.

Certification

In backend development at gebeya training, soft skils at dereja academy, English language at h2, hackathon certified, ICT certified.